Damien D. Hebert (409)-888-0036 Houston, Texas DamienHebert710@gmail.com

My Portfolio

https://www.linkedin.com/in/damien-hebert-5590b49a

To whom it may concern,

Hello my name Damien!

I am currently a Environmental Field Tech for Target Emissions/ Montrose Environmental Group. I work with the LDAR program as a third party contractor locating leaks throughout the plant to ensure EPA regulations are met. Although I have been employed here for 2 years, I've decided that I wanted a more fulfilling role in my career path.

This year in August I completed my full stack coding bootcamp through Rice University. There I learned a vast amount with regards to front end development as well as back end development. From hours of debugging JavaScript code to building tables through MySQL and MongoDB.

Saying this is one of the hardest yet fulfilling things I've done would be an understatement.

Though I am new to web development, I hope the skills detailed in my resume meets all the requirements you're looking for. I am eager and excited to start this new career path and meet the challenges that are ahead.

Hoping to hear from you soon!

Best regards,

Skills

- Proficient in front end languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.js
- JavaScript back end languages using Node.js and Express.js
- Proficient in utilizing MySQL to maintain/update databases as well as using NoSQL databases such as MongoDB and GraphQL
- Have a well understanding with processing requests from server using Express.js Frameworks
- Working on group projects while asynchronous within a group setting via Zoom
- Quality control analysis regarding documentation of components within field
- Conducting tests and inspections of products, services, or processes to evaluate quality or performance.
- Troubleshooting and calibrating instruments to match leak thresholds
- Instruct safety meetings prior to field work
- Communicating with operators and technicians in the field
- Notifying instrument technicians of leaks throughout chemical plant

Experience:

Sept 8, 2020 – currently employed

Target Emissions/ Montrose Environmental Group

Freeport, Tx

Environmental Field Technician

- Utilize knowledge of field equipment to tag and document valves/connectors in multiple facilities on-site at FreeportLNG.
- Analyze and understand P&IDs to locate their corresponding parts in the field. Also, use PI&Ds to perform Quality Assurance/ Quality Control of our database.

- Use an OGI Camera and a Method 21 Bascom Turner device to scan field equipment and components for leaks, in conjunction with proprietary mobile applications for quantifying and documenting the leaks.
- Coordinate and develop rapport with facility operators as well as other contractors to ensure completion of work in a timely, efficient manner
- OSHA10, TWIC and Houston Basic Plus Orientation certified.
- Scanning 350-400 components a day during Method 21 scan within facility
- During OGI camera scans, 6 videos per work day was completed.

March 2018 - March 2020

Best Buy

Beaumont, Tx

Inventory Specialist

- Packaging and distributing
- Managing store pickups
- Store security, Asset protection
- Processing incoming truck shipment and validating high commodity items such as Apple,
 Samsung
- Efficient in warehouse organizing, using "Big Joe" platform lift to safely down stock and up stock appliances such as washers, dryers, refrigerators, gas ovens, etc.

April 2017 – March 2018

Academy

Beaumont, Tx

Customer Service Representative

- Money management, returns/exchanges
- Stock replenishing

July 2016 – February 2018

Zumiez

Beaumont, Tx

2nd Assistant Manager

- Opening and closing store
- Managing bank deposits for store
- Meeting daily, weekly, and monthly personal sales goals and developing new potential recruits to meet theirs as well.

Education:

Lamar Institute of Technology

Jan. 2017 – Dec. 2019

Beaumont, Tx

Associate's in Instrumentation Tech.

Rice University Coding Bootcamp

Glasscock School of Continuing Studies

Feb. 2022 - Aug. 2022

Houston, Texas

West Brook Senior High School

August 2009 - May 2013

References:

Caleb Bryant

Environmental Field Tech

Target Emissions Services/ Montrose Environmental

(409)-549-1632

Stephen Crayton

Field Engineer for Entact (409)-767-2511

Edward Ardoin

Airgas Representative

(409)-363-2021